Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/aduwu-joseph-483b91163 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Apache Kafka

Next.js

NestJS

Certifications

Project Management Professional (PMP)

Environmental, Health and Safety Certifications (BEAC)

Project Management Professional (PMP)

Aduwu Joseph

Software Engineer | Database Designer | Analyst | Entrepreneur Abuja, Federal Capital Territory, Nigeria

Summary

I have over 4 years proficiency experience in agile development environment with full understanding and practice of the system development life cycle (SDLC) using C#, .NET 7, 6 & 5, .Net Core 3.1, 2.2, 2.1, .Net Framework 4.5, 4.6, Entity Framework, Dapper, Java Spring Boot, Java SE, EE & Web.

Cloud experience with Azure and Bit Bucket, DevOps and CI/CD, Git, Docker, and project management using Jira, and Trello, Agile

Database proficiency: SQL, MySQL, MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite.

Other skills

- 1. Front end: HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, JQuery, Bootstrap, and Angular
- 2. Skilled in Internet of Things (IoT) using C++ on Arduino and Biometric Fingerprint Integration
- 3. Good Microsoft Office Skills

Experience

Zarttech

Back End Developer

October 2023 - Present (4 months)

Remote

First City Monument Bank Limited
Back End Developer
October 2022 - Present (1 year 4 months)
Lagos State, Nigeria

Develop and manage API and all back-end integration support

Exaro Enterprise Solutions Limited Software Developer

Page 1 of 3

April 2021 - September 2022 (1 year 6 months)

Abuja, Federal Capital Territory, Nigeria

Worked closely with Product Managers and Integration managers to strategize and develop web services and REST/RESTful APIs endpoints to allow seamless communication and data transfer between two of our products we want to interface with each other.

Worked on enterprise applications (Healthcare Systems) using Asp.Net C#, visual studio, Bootstrap, jQuery, AJAX, Javascript, ensuring continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) using Azure DevOps.

Worked with database designer to develop well normalize enterprise application databases with MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB

First Digit Communications Ltd Lead Software Engineer December 2018 - March 2021 (2 years 4 months) Abuja

Guide team development efforts towards successful project delivery. Provide technical leadership to teammates through coaching and mentor-ship.

Maintain high standards of software quality within the team by establishing good practices and habits.

Identify and encourage areas for growth and improvement within the team. Collaborate with other software developers, business analysts and software architects to plan, design, develop, test, and maintain web-and desktop-based business applications built on Microsoft technologies.

Assist in the collection and documentation of user's requirements, development of user stories, estimates and work plans.

Prepare reports, manuals and other documentation on the status, operation and maintenance of software.

Design, develop, and unit test applications in accordance with established standards.

Participate in peer-reviews of solution designs and related code.

Package and support deployment of releases.

Work with teammates in the migration of legacy applications to current Microsoft technologies.

Develop, refine, and tune integrations between applications.

Analyze and resolve technical and application problems.

Assess opportunities for application and process improvement and prepare documentation of rationale to share with team members and other affected parties.

Adhere to high-quality development principles while delivering solutions ontime and on-budget.

Provide third-level support to business users.

Research and evaluate a variety of software products.

G7 Bridge Technologies Ltd Software Trainer and IT Consultant April 2017 - May 2018 (1 year 2 months) Makurdi, Benue, Nigeria

Create and execute learning strategies and programs for industrial attachment (IT) students on full stack software development.

Evaluate individual and organizational development needs Implement various learning methods(e.g. coaching, job-shadowing, online training)

Design and deliver e-learning courses, workshops and other trainings
Assess the success of development plans and help IT students make the most
of learning opportunities

Education

University of Agriculture, Makurdi

Bachelor of Mathematics and Computer Science , Mathematics and Computer Science \cdot (April 2015 - September 2017)

Panet Technologies Limited

Diploma, Computer Software Engineering · (2013 - 2014)

Nigerian Army Institute of Technology and Environmental Studies (NAITES), Makurdi

National Diploma, Computer Science · (2011 - 2013)